<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blogging | RuiOnWriting.NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://ruionwriting.net/blog/categories/blogging/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ruionwriting.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-12T22:20:56+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://ruionwriting.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rui Marques]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Try something new: Octopress motivation]]></title>
    <link href="http://ruionwriting.net/blog/2013/09/21/try-something-new-octopress-motivation/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-21T15:28:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ruionwriting.net/blog/2013/09/21/try-something-new-octopress-motivation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Real blogging, like <a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/">Scott Hanselman</a> does (and many others), is a serious thing that requires discipline and a personal commitment. I’ve failed to do anything even close <em>(&lt;1%???)</em> of what Scott does concerning sharing with the community real stuff that teach and empower any developer skills.<!-- more --></p>

<h2 id="im-a-failed-blogger">I’m a failed blogger</h2>
<p>I’ve a lot of excuses that sum up to NO TIME. What??? The truth is that I didn’t really enforce a discipline to blogging and the excuse about not having spare time and patience fitted just perfectly all this time. 3 years after my first blog post I have to try something new: a personal commitment to write something useful and clear with more regularity.</p>

<h2 id="i-want-to-learn-more">I want to learn more</h2>
<p>Blogging about findings/opinions (personal) related to my job daily challenges, problems and solutions is an opportunity to be a better programmer, person (yes, I work also with people) and ultimately a better professional. </p>

<h2 id="why-octopress">Why Octopress?</h2>
<p>Why not? I love <a href="http://git-scm.com/">git</a> and I want to learn new stuff so Octopress seems to be the perfect framework for it. Any Windows/.NET guy with some linux exposure will gain some extra skills in the process (empowers extra curiosity for Windows guts). Octopress it is, exiting confort zone…</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
